Finding Aid for the Adaline Caroline Guenther Papers LSC.1150
UCLA Library Special Collections
Adaline Caroline Guenther papers
1942-1975
UCLA Library Special Collections
Guenther, Adaline Caroline
LSC.1150
5.0 Linear Feet (10 boxes)
The collection is composed of correspondence, photographs, typescripts, and memorabilia; it has a double focus, the American Veterans Committee and Adaline Guenther herself.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Adaline Guenther, 1973.
Gift of Shirley Hine, 1976 and 1978.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9914706873606533
Biography
Guenther was born in 1897; became chief administrator of the University Religious Conference at UCLA at its inception in 1927, and later served as its executive director (1945-59); she was one of founders of Unicamp, the UCLA student-run summer camp for underprivileged children; also a founder of Student Board, an interdenominational student discussion group, and of Project India, an anti-communist group in the 1950s; edited letters of servicemen connected with the University Religious Conference into a newsletter, and held together the correspondence which evolved into the American Veterans Committee; the Committee, founded as a counterforce to the American Legion, was an organization of educated liberal veterans; died in 1975.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence, typescripts, photographs and memorabilia relating to the American Veterans Committee, Guenther's work at the University Religious Conference, her friendship with John Ehrlichman and Gilbert Harrison, and her personal affairs. Correspondents include: Tom Bradley, Dorothy Buffum Chandler, Otis Chandler, John Ehrlichman, Gilbert Harrison, Merle Miller, Eleanor Roosevelt, and Wendell Willkie.
Collection Description
Adaline Guenther (1897-1975) was Executive Director of the University Religious Conference from 1945 until her retirement in 1959 and had been its chief administrator since its inception in 1927. She was one of the founders of UniCamp (a student-run summer camp for underpriveleged children, Studen board (an interdenominational discussion group of campus student leaders), and Project india (a student-to-student approach to fighting Communism in India in the 1950s), and through these programs significantly shapped UCLA's extracullicular life. She was a woman of great mental and spiritual vitality with a gift for guiding others to examine their goals and shape their minds. This is apparent throughout the entire collection, from the long letters from servicemen in W.W.II answering her questions about racial discrimination in the armed forces to the book reviews she prepared at 77 for the members of her retirement community. The journal she kept in the year before her death records her perceptions of the "victories and defeats of aging."
The first seven boxes are early American Veterans Committee documentation, mainly in the form of letters to Guenther from approximately 150 servicemen formerly connected with the University Religious Conference at UCLA. She edited their letters into a newsletter ("10845") and held together the correspondence which evolved into the AVC. It was conceived as a counterforce to the American Legion, a veterans' organization of educated liberals who would shape the postwar world. The original letters have a wide range of personality and subject matter_. There are highly articulate soldiers writing about their reaction to the atom bomb, a Japanese-American and a conscientious objector writing from their respective internment camps, wives of soldiers writing personal letters to Guenther, soldiers writing to Guenther out of loneliness and boredom. They talk about peace, democracy, racial equality, religion, army life, UniCamp, revisions to revisions of the AVC official policy statements. Gil Harrison wrote voluminously, involved in deciding every detail of AVC development. There are also letters from prominent people agreeing or declining to be associated with AVC. Eleanor Roosevelt is the most significant of these.
Guenther's later correspondence includes letters from Mayor Tom Bradley, Bishop John Krumm, Rabbi Edgar Magnin and other leaders in the fields of religion, education and civic life. John Ehrlichman was one of the students who passed through the URC; Guenther was repelled by Watergate but attempted through correspondence with Judge John Sirica to have Ehrlichman's sentence lightened because of her personal loyalty to Ehrlichman and his wife.
Adaline Guenther was the subject of an oral history at UCLA; she discusses the AVC at some length. Another oral history was compiled from interviews with people who participated in Project India and contains some comments on Guenther.
The item count below includes clippings and small candid photographs; formal studio portraits are in Box 10. Many AVC people are represented.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
American Veterans Committee, ca. 1942-45 (boxes 1-6)
Guenther correspondence with Gilbert Harrison (box 7)
Guenther's personal papers, ca. 1952-75 (boxes 7-8)
Memorabilia (boxes 9-10).
Related Material
The gift of a mind [oral history transcript] / Adaline C. Guenther, interviewee. UCLA Oral History Department interview, 1974. Available at UCLA Library Special Collections.
University of California, Los Angeles. University Religious Conference -- Archives; American Veterans Committee.; Guenther, Adaline Caroline, 1897-1975 --Archives.; University of California, Los Angeles. University Religious Conference -- Administration
- American Veterans Committee, ca. 1942-1945
  - ABCD misc., (22 items, 44 pieces) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Veterans Committee., (18 items, 29 pieces) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Veterans Committee., (20 items, 41 pieces) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Veterans Committee, "10845" bulletins., (17 items, 26 pieces) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Phil Baker., (18 items, 26 pieces) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Janice Beavon (Gravely)., (10 items, 18 pieces) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Tony Berardo., (22 items, 43 pieces) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Max Bernoff, (18 items, 22 pieces) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - David Black, (4 items, 5 pieces) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Robert Bohl, (11 items, 16 pieces) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Charle and Mary Bolté., (20 items, 32 pieces) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Robert Bomeisher., (10 items, 14 pieces) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Malcolm Brown., (8 items, 13 pieces) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Robert Brown., (15 items, 24 pieces) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bill Bryan., (2 items, 4 pieces) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - John Bryant., (3 items, 4 pieces) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bill and Jean Burke., (19 items, 40 pieces) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - John Burnside., (8 items, 10 pieces) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - B.F. Burton., (12 items, 18 pieces) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Babs White Cable., (10 items, 31 pieces) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - John Caldecott., (12 items, 31 pieces) (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Bruce Cassiday., (3 items, 6 pieces) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Steve Cavanaugh., (13 items, 27 pieces) (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Al Chamie., (3 items, 3 pieces) (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Hal Cherness., (7 items, 10 pieces) (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Muzzy Chesy., (4 items, 5 pieces) (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Civilian Grandchildren., (33 items, 45 pieces) (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Frank Clancy., (3 items, 9 pieces) (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Louise Morely Cochran., (21 item, 38 pieces) (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Leon Cooper., (1 item, 2 pieces) (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Roy and Betsey Covert., (9 items, 14 pieces) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Cliff and Ruth Dancer., (18 items, 47 pieces) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Cliff and Ruth Dancer., (20 items, 36 pieces) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Cliff and Ruth Dancer., (20 items, 40 pieces) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Cliff and Ruth Dancer., (20 items, 38 pieces) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Cliff and Ruth Dancer., (20 items, 46 pieces) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Cliff and Ruth Dancer., (20 items, 41 pieces) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Cliff and Ruth Dancer., (20 items, 37 pieces) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Bill Delaney., (7 items, 9 pieces) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Bud Desenberg., (3 items, 4 pieces) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Morris Dill., (7 items, 25 pieces) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Frank Dooley., (4 items, 12 pieces) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Ed. Dorris., (5 items, 11 pieces) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Bill and Tom Duddleson., (20 items, 42 pieces) (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Bill and Tom Duddleson., (20 items, 29 pieces) (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Max Dunn., (26 items, 48 pieces) (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - E and F miscellaneous., (20 items, 51 pieces) (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - E and F miscellaneous., (20 items, 44 pieces) (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Bob Elliott., (11 items, 29 pieces) (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Charles Ferguson., (11 items, 13 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Luke Fishburn., (17 items, 35 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Phil Fleeman., (12 items, 40 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Seymour Freed., (22 items, 45 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Bob Frese., (30 items, 53 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Bob Frese., (29 items, 34 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Dotty and Guy Freutel., (15 items, 38 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - G and H miscellaneous., (24 items, 52 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Hal Gillian., (15 items, 25 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Al and Fay Grass., (29 items, 65 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Bill Gray., (7 items, 19 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Bob Griggs., (2 items, 4 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Maury Grossman., (3 items, 3 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Thomas Grubbs., (1 item, 3 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Scope and Contents note
    [Was filed in XYZ misc.] Re Japanese-Americans in detention camps.
  - H miscellaneous., (12 items, 26 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Bill Halpin., (2 items, 2 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Hanford Files., (18 items, 30 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Hanford Files., (16 items, 31 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Bob Hannah., (1 item, 2 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Dick Harris., (5 items, 14 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 20)
    General note
    [Dil Harrison filed separately as Box 7]
  - Jack Hauptli., (13 items, 28 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Dick Hayden., (9 items, 35 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Louis Hayward., (11 items, 26 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - John Henry., (18 items, 63 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - John Henry., (18 items, 47 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Bill Hensey., (6 items, 12 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - John Hessell., (3 items, 4 pieces) (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Bob Hine., (29 items, 45 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Dick Horton., (14 items, 26 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 1 and J miscellaneous., (11 items, 14 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Sam and Clyde Johnson., (20 items, 41 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Sam and Clyde Johnson., (28 items, 32 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - John Joseph., (10 items, 27 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - K and L miscellaneous., (16 items, 34 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - K and L miscellaneous., (15 items, 48 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Al Kositch., (17 items, 38 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - John Krumm., (6 items, 12 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Ed Ladd., (22 items, 39 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Dean La Field., (13 items, 27 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Bob Levin., (21 item, 26 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Mendel Lieberman., (5 items, 17 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Wadsworth Likely., (20 items, 22 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Wadsworth Likely., (20 items, 33 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Wadsworth Likely., (20 items, 36 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Wadsworth Likely., (10 items, 19 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - James Lu Valle., (11 items, 21 pieces) (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - M and N miscellaneous., (19 items, 33 pieces) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Ben Masaoka., (5 items, 10 pieces) (Box 5, Folder 2)
    [Japanese-American]
  - Ben Masaoka., (3 items, 9 pieces) (Box 5, Folder 3)
    [Was filed with Civilian Grandchildren]
  - Gerry McClellan., (27 items, 44 pieces) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Don Marsh., (20 items, 31 pieces) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Don Marsh., (20 items, 35 pieces) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Don Marsh., (20 items, 39 pieces) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Don Marsh., (23 items, 23 pieces) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Don Marsh., (23 items, 36 pieces) (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Rex May., (15 items, 50 pieces) (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Ed McHale., (27 items, 65 pieces) (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Merle Miller., (2 items, 2 pieces) (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Sandy and Flora Mock., (12 items, 23 pieces) (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Farlan Myers., (12 items, 25 pieces) (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - OPQ miscellaneous., (5 items, 9 pieces) (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Bill Oakie., (3 items, 8 pieces) (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - John Odisho., (8 items, 17 pieces) (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Eddie Pike., (31 item, 46 pieces) (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Harry Pregerson., (21 item, 55 pieces) (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Dick Pryne., (25 items, 56 pieces) (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - RST miscellaneous., (18 items, 39 pieces) (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - RST miscellaneous., (18 items, 24 pieces) (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Stuart Ratliff., (5 items, 6 pieces) (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Dick Rogan., (5 items, 5 pieces) (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Bill Rogers., (1 item, 1 pieces) (Box 5, Folder 25)
    [Was filed with American Veterans Committee]
  - Eleanor Roosevelt., (4 items, 4 pieces) (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Eleanor Roosevelt., (1 item, 1 pieces) (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Eleanor Roosevelt., (5 items, 7 pieces) (Box 5, Folder 28)
    [Was filed with Gil Harrison]
  - James and Norma Rose., (24 items, 43 pieces) (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Francis and Peggy Scannell., (27 items, 51 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Bill and Carolyn Schaefer., (8 items, 8 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Bob Schiller., (18 items, 26 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Norman Schutt., (7 items, 15 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Albert Sessarego., (11 items, 30 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Danny Sheehy., (20 items, 24 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Danny Sheehy., (16 items, 35 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Danny Sheehy., (20 items, 45 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Johnny Slevin., (14 items, 33 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 9)
    [Conscientious objector in Civilian Public Service]
  - Quentin Smith., (12 items, 17 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Alex Sokoloff., (6 items, 8 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Sam Spencer., (17 items, 29 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Sam Spencer., (15 items, 29 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Jack Stanley., (5 items, 9 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Gordon Stanton., (2 items, 3 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Malcolm Steinlauf., (4 items, 4 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Rex Stout., (1 item, 1 piece) (Box 6, Folder 17)
    [Was filed with Wadsworth Likely]
  - Bob Streeton., (12 items, 31 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Kevin Sweeney., (3 items, 4 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Charles Thacher., (18 items, 36 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Bobby Jo Thomas., (8 items, 11 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - UVW miscellaneous., (14 items, 18 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Chris Wain., (18 items, 24 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Bob Walker., (7 items, 12 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Exie Stevens Warner., (28 items, 53 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Ernest Weiner., (2 items, 4 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Wendell Willkie., (1 item, 1 piece) (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Max Willardson., (5 items, 18 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - WXYZ miscellaneous., (2 items, 5 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Howard Young., (2 items, 2 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Gramma's 10845., (23 items, 58 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Guenther Personal., (21 item, 29 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 32)
    [Mainly post-war]
  - Guenther Personal., (20 items, 38 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 33)
    [Post-war]
  - Guenther Personal., (5 items, 25 pieces) (Box 6, Folder 34)
    [From John Ehrlichman]
- Gil Harrison Correspondence.
  Letters to Harrison from Eleanor Roosevelt are filed in Box 5 under her name.
  - Letters from Harrison., (20 items, 28 pieces) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Letters from Harrison., (20 items, 30 pieces) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Letters from Harrison., (20 items, 35 pieces) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Letters from Harrison., (20 items, 29 pieces) (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Letters from Harrison., (20 items, 47 pieces) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Letters from Harrison., (20 items, 25 pieces) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Letters from Harrison., (20 items, 33 pieces) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Letters from Harrison., (20 items, 32 pieces) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Letters from Harrison., (20 items, 45 pieces) (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Letters from Harrison., (20 items, 36 pieces) (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Letters from Harrison., (20 items, 34 pieces) (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Letters from Harrison., (20 items, 36 pieces) (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Letters from Harrison., (20 items, 29 pieces) (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Letters from Harrison., (8 items, 11 pieces) (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Letters to Harrison., (16 items, 46 pieces) (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Letters to Harrison., (12 items, 25 pieces) (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Guenther's Personal papers, ca. 1952-1975.
  - Medical and legal., (19 items, 23 pieces) (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous letters, 1935-1957.; (15 items, 29 pieces) (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous letters, 1971-1974.; (27 items, 35 pieces) (Box 7, Folder 19)
    Includes letters from Tom Bradley, John Krumm, Otis Chandler, Sot Lesser and Edgar Magnin.
  - Letters from Robert Jaffie., (15 items, 34 pieces) (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Letters from Robert Jaffie., (20 items, 45 pieces) (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Letters from Robert Jaffie., (20 items, 28 pieces) (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Letters to re "Gramma Goes to Church", (26 items, 27 pieces) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Letters to re "Gramma Goes to Church.", (26 items, 32 pieces) (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - "Gramma Goes to Church" clippings., (22 items) (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - "Gramma Goes to Church" clippings., (22 items) (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - "Gramma Goes to Church" clippings., (22 items) (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - "Gramma Goes to Church" clippings., (22 items) (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous material re UniCamp dinner in Guenther's honor, February 6, 1975.; (13 items, 38 pieces) (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Letters to re retirement from University Religious Conference, 1959.; (5 items, 5 pieces) (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Los Angeles Times Woman of the Year Award article and program, 1952.; (3 items, 5 pieces) (Box 8)
    Includes letter from Dorothy Buffum Chandler.
  - Notes for speech given by Guenther at Mt. San Antonio Gardens, n.d.; (1 item, 8 pieces) (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Letters re chairmanship of Health Services Committee at Mt. San Antonio Gardens, n.d.; (4 items, 4 pieces) (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous material re University Service Award from UCLA, June 1, 1974.; (24 items, 36 pieces) (Box 8, Folder 12)
    Contains 3 photographs of Guenther and Mayor Tom Bradley items, letter from Bradley, text of Bradley's presentation speech.
  - Miscellaneous material from Steven Muller., (6 items, 10 pieces) (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous material from Gil Harrison., (6 items, 14 pieces) (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Letters from John Ehrlichman, 1969-1973.; (11 items, 17 pieces) (Box 8, Folder 15)
    Includes an official invitation to the 1973 inauguration of Richard Nixon.
  - Correspondence with Ehrlichman re Robert Takeuchi, 1972.; (5 items, 7 pieces); [Mainly photocopies] (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Letters to Judge John Sirica from Guenther, Ehrlichman and Herman Agoyo (Executive Director, Eight Northern Indian Pueblos Council), (6 items, 10 pieces) (Box 8, Folder 17)
    re Ehrlichman's Watergate sentence items, 1974. [Includes some photocopies]
  - Book reviews by Guenther while at Mt. San Antonio Gardens., (42 leaves) (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Guenther's journal, August 10 to December 3, 1974.; (20 leaves) (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Guenther's journal., (21 leaves) (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Guenther's journal., (19 leaves) (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Guenther's journal., (20 leaves) (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Guenther's journal., (23 leaves) (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Enclosures found with journal., (12 items, 22 pieces) (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous., (10 items, 14 pieces) (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Guenther's transcript, Ohio Wesleyan University., (1 piece) (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Materials relating to Guenther's death and memorial service., (25 items, 32 pieces) (Box 8, Folder 27)
    Includes typescript of Gil Harrison's eulogy with corrections in his hand.
  - Research material, (photocopies only); (23 items, 45 pieces) (Box 8, Folder 28)
    Material collected by UCLA Oral History Program on the University Religious Conference. [Not a part of Guenther's original papers]
- Memorabilia
  - Account book, Guenther's personal budget, 1971-1974. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - B.A. diploma, Ohio Wesleyan University. (Box 9)
  - Diploma, in case, honorary doctoral degree from Ohio Wesleyan University, 1953. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Doctora1 hood. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    [moved to Box 10]
  - "Experience and Activities of an Ambassador of the Most High and His" [by Guenther's father?], typescript in leather folder, 139 1eaves (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - "My Seven Indian Summers" by Guenther, typescript in binder, 287 leaves. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Guenther's account of Project India.
  - Two medallions, UCLA Distinguished Service Award. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    One encased in plastic and dated 1974, one on ribbon, n.d. Phi Beta Kappa key attached.
  - Three passports. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - 4 small society pins, in envelope. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Silver cup, Los Angeles Times Woman of the Year award, 1952. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Notes of a meeting of the 500 Club at which Gilbert Harrison was the special guest., April 15, 1942; Typed carbon copy, folder. (Box 9, Folder 11)
    Addition, donated March, 1978.
  - Miscellany (Box 9, Folder 12)
    re. Thomas St. Clair Evans, organizer and first executive of the University Religious Conference: "An ode to Mr. Evans on his birthday"; "A tribute ... at the time of his retirement from the University Religious Conference, Apr. 30, 1942," including an appreciation by Gilbert Harrison.
  - Miscellany (Box 9, Folder 13)
    re. Guenther: poem, "The sweetheart of Student Board (or, Gram Guenther fight song)"; various newsclippings on her career. Folder (5, 6).
  - Guenther's journal, round-the-world trip with her sister Esther, August 5, ? - Mar. 8, ? (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Formal portrait photographs, possibly of UCLA students Doctoral hood., 4 folders. (Box 10)